

PROFILE & OBJECTIVE

I have near about 4 Years of working experience as GIS Engineer. Now I'm seeking for a quality environment where my knowledge can be shared and enriched. Looking for opportunity where I can improve my quality and skills, which offers me for long-term advancement and growth.

* Nearly 30 days Notice Period.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH:

12-03-1997

ADDRESS:

211, Reliable Pride Apartment, Somasudarapalya, HSR Layout, Bangalore, Karnataka – 560102

Permanent Address:

Pratapnagar (Badartala), Arambagh, Hooghly, West Bengal, India - 712415

CONTACT

PHONE:

9091095337*

* Please note that, due to limited cellular reception in my area, I am best reached by phone Monday—Thursday after 1:30 PM IST. Anytime in WhatsApp/mail. Thank you for your understanding.

WhatsApp [online almost all day]:

Chat without save the number: https://wa.me/9091095337?text=Hi

EMAIL:

mirjanalisha@gmail.com

ONLINE RESUME (Website):

https://mirjanalisha.github.io

LINKEDIN ID:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirjanalisha

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

BENGALI: COLLOQUIAL HINDI: GOOD ENGLISH: GOOD

MIRJAN ALI SHA

GIS Engineer, Nurture Farm Agtech Pvt. Ltd.

EDUCATION

VIDYASAGAR UNIVERSITY, *M.Sc. in Remote Sensing and GIS* 2018 – 2020

CGPA: 8.44

IBM Skills Network (Couserα), Professional Certificate in Data Science and Machine Learning
2019 – 2020 9 Courses

IIIT – Bangalore (Upgrad Online), *Certification on Business Analytics* 2022 – 2023 6 months

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nurture (AFS) Agtech Pvt. Ltd, GIS Engineer (ML-GIS Department) Bangalore | May 2022 to Present

- Working on Burn Detection, Tillage Detection, Bailing Detection, Tile Framework etc. and developing Kubernetes pipeline using different tools.
- Build full pipeline from raw MSI/SAR tile data to ingesting insights to DB, logging every step using PySpark and below cloud tools.
- Farm boundary detection using MRCNN (earlier), improved version with SAM-MRCNN using mapbox tiles.
- Working with Big Data using PySpark, AWS Athena Query (using python), AWS S3 storage, GitLab, Docker, Jenkins, AWS ECR (Docker Image Repo), Kubernetes CLI (kubectl), Spinnaker (Kubernetes 2.0), Kubernetes Dashboard, Logs etc. Prometheus, Grafana for Kubernetes Logs, Scheduling Kubernetes Jobs, Azure Databricks.
- Working with Geospatial Data and Sustain Projects using Python, Google Earth Engine and QGIS for Sustainability Projects.

SkyMap Global Pvt. Ltd, GIS Engineer Kolkata | September-2021 to March-2022

 Administrative Mapping Project: Village level Administrative Layout making, three tier Administrative Boundary creation and Database updating.

Aabsys IT Pvt. Ltd, GIS / CAD Engineer Bhubaneswar | March-2021 to September-2021

- Navigation Mapping Project: City level Road and Local Administrative boundary extraction and validate using surveyed geotagged photos.
- Working with ArcGIS Python Toolbox, ArcGIS Modeler and Python to develop some tools that help co-workers to speed up the work.

OTHERS TRAINING AND COURSES

UCDEVIS University of California [Coursera Online]

2020-2021 [6 Months]

Geographic Information System (GIS) Specialization

IIRS-ISRO Outreach Programme, Basics of RS, GIS and GNSS (90 hours), Overview of Geo-processing using Python (13 hours, 30 minutes) 2020, 2021

ESRI Online Training [MOOC Courses], **Do-It-Yourself Geo Apps** (4 weeks), **Cartography** (6 weeks), **Spatial Data Science** (6 weeks), **The Location Advantage** (6 weeks).

2019, 2020

Standford Online [Coursera Online], Machine Learning

2019 - 2020

SKILLS OR WORKING WITH TECHNOLOGIES BELOW:

ArcGIS & ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, ENVI & ERDAS Imagine, AutoCAD Map 3D, SPSS, Advance Excel, Word (Docs), PowerPoint (Slides), Jira, Zoho – (Project Management Tool) Sustainability Projects (Carbon Credit), GeoServer, PostareSQL (PostGIS), Python, PySpark, Databricks (Python), AWS S3, AWS Athena Query, AWS ECR, Jenkins, GitLab, Kubernetes, Spinnaker, Google Earth Engine (JavaScript), R Programming Language, Tableau, Power BI SQL, TensorFlow,

PROJECTS OUTSIDE WORKING EXPERIENCE

Python (PyPi) Packages (For all new packages, please visit:

https://pypi.org/user/mirjanalisha/):

• Open GeoData API (pip install open-geodata-api):

Open Geodata API provides seamless access to multiple open geospatial data APIs (Planetary Computer, Earth Search) with automatic URL management, intelligent filtering, and maximum flexibility for data reading, processing, downloading data with it's core STAC management.

• AI Research Planner (pip install ai-research-planner) [Still InProgress]: Al-powered research planning and execution system that creates intelligent research plans and gathers comprehensive data from the internet.

AstroKundali (pip install astrokundali):

Generate and plot North-Indian Lagna Kundali charts using pyswisseph. Flexible astrokundali package with Different house calculation methods and interpretation JSONs.

Why Astrokundali (Astrology)?

Not afraid to learn completely different subject, even different culture. It was my
one of the initial days projects which help me to understand OOP in python
projects.

QGIS Plugins (For all new plugins, please visit:

https://plugins.qgis.org/search/?q=Mirjan+Ali+Sha):

➤ Band Stacker ≥:

A plugin to stack bands from selected raster layers.

Clear Null Geometry :

This plugin deletes all NULL geometry from the shapefile. New users of QGIS easily creates NULL geometry to shapefiles when they trying to delete a geometry and facing difficulties to delete all of them easily, this plugin will help them to delete all NULL geometry from all selected layers. **Work without opening any dialog boxes.**

CRS Finder :

Intelligent Coordinate Reference System finder and assign projection to the Layer on the fly. Creating QGIS DockWidget and extensively used temp file and updating continuously on it.

➤ Export 2KML 🗟:

Export multiple/single vector and raster layer/s into a single KML or KMZ with QGIS styling. And you have full options (all KML properties) for your output KML/KMZ. Creating png preview files for raster data.

➤ Mosaic Tool :

A plugin to mosaic bands from selected raster layers. **Creating QGIS Processing Tool and Tool Group.**

Supervised Classifier :

Classify Raster Using Shapefile (.shp). A plugin to classify a selected raster file with reference. **Use external dependency like scikit-learn.**

Unsupervised Classifier :::

Plugin for unsupervised classification (clustering) of satellite images. **Use external dependency like scikit-learn.**

CSV Geometry Export ::

Export vector layers as CSV files with geometry and customizable column names. Creating QGIS Context menu and positioned to a desired position.